<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://jiangtao639.github.io/jianglab/</id>
    <title>TAOJay &amp; Eating&apos;s Blog</title>
    <updated>2020-04-29T08:48:42.577Z</updated>
    <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://jiangtao639.github.io/jianglab/"/>
    <link rel="self" href="https://jiangtao639.github.io/jianglab/atom.xml"/>
    <subtitle>为了更好的明天加油！</subtitle>
    <logo>https://jiangtao639.github.io/jianglab/images/avatar.png</logo>
    <icon>https://jiangtao639.github.io/jianglab/favicon.ico</icon>
    <rights>All rights reserved 2020, TAOJay &amp; Eating&apos;s Blog</rights>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[学会加Audio和Video啦！]]></title>
        <id>https://jiangtao639.github.io/jianglab/post/xue-hui-jia-audio-he-video-la/</id>
        <link href="https://jiangtao639.github.io/jianglab/post/xue-hui-jia-audio-he-video-la/">
        </link>
        <updated>2020-04-29T08:41:17.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<audio controls>
    <source src="https://m801.music.126.net/20200429171145/9d63b74ac23dee8f39c5315fd2105963/jdyyaac/0f5e/030b/0e08/847e2c6ce04a9e8d7af39bcf66c0be87.m4a" type="audio/mpeg">
    </audio>
<p>说好不哭(⊙﹏⊙)</p>
<video width="1000" height="500" controls>
        <source src="https://apd-d59eb41d265adc96a2616c48aba8c01a.v.smtcdns.com/mv.music.tc.qq.com/A-3brXzK-tId6fZLw8xcNYteCOdvB-FwR1RVBsX4vZDc/E3BFDE5AF0BE1B66294E3546CDC59C5215257ECC33F12D93B5943C5B42DF14497C0E3F04C03001AF5EC1C56E868EDD83ZZqqmusic_default/qmmv_0a6bzqxhaibvsraha4caqaiiaqgvnw4xq2xd4453iqcagdygb4ea.f9844.mp4?fname=qmmv_0a6bzqxhaibvsraha4caqaiiaqgvnw4xq2xd4453iqcagdygb4ea.f9844.mp4" type="video/mp4">
</video>]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Where 'Quarantine' Comes From]]></title>
        <id>https://jiangtao639.github.io/jianglab/post/where-quarantine-comes-from/</id>
        <link href="https://jiangtao639.github.io/jianglab/post/where-quarantine-comes-from/">
        </link>
        <updated>2020-04-29T02:30:07.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Audio src: https://learningenglish.voanews.com/a/where-quarantine-comes-from/5357370.html<br>
In human history, the spread of infectious diseases to mass numbers of people is not uncommon. Pandemics, historians say, started when we humans began farming land and living in communities. Pandemics increased as trade between communities and nations increased.</p>
<p>From smallpox to influenza to the plague, there was often no medical treatment to prevent or cure these diseases. Take for example, the plague that hit Europe in the 14th century. It is also known as the “Black Death.”</p>
<p>With no medical prevention available, isolating the sick was the only effective public health defense. With many other pandemics, the best chance at prevention was to keep sick people away from healthy people. This is called a quarantine.</p>
<p>And that is our word for today.</p>
<p>Word experts at Merriam-Webster explain that the word “quarantine” has both French and Italian influences.</p>
<p>In the late 1400s, English speakers borrowed the French word quarantaine which means “a period of about 40 days.” Quarante is the word for the number 40 (forty) in French.</p>
<p>At that time, quarantaine had a religious meaning. Some word experts say it refers to the period of time Jesus spent fasting -- going without food -- in the desert.</p>
<p>However, over time, people began using it for more than just religious situations. For example, it referred to the delay of putting a legal agreement in place. In the early 1500s, quarantine also was used to describe a &quot;period of 40 days in which a widow has the right to remain in her dead husband's house.”</p>
<p>Around the same time, other city-states in Europe were also using a similar word -- quarantena. This word was used to mean the “isolation of a ship to protect the port city from potential disease.”</p>
<p>The Centers for Disease Control and Prevention explains on its website that “quarantine was first introduced in 1377 on Croatia’s Dalmatian Coast.”</p>
<p>By the 1600s, English speakers began using quarantena to mean “isolation as protection from disease.” As the French form of this word (quarantaine) was already being used, English kept it but gave it a new meaning. It was now an English word based on French spelling -- with an Italian definition and Latin roots.</p>
<p>In North America in the late 1600s, quarantine was introduced to control yellow fever. The CDC says this was the case in New York (1688) and in Boston (1691).</p>
<p>That’s the word history. Now, let’s talk about how to use “quarantine” in a sentence.</p>
<p>For starters, it is both a noun and a verb.</p>
<p>As a noun, we often use it after the preposition “under.” If someone is under quarantine, they are required to physically keep away from others. For example: “When she was under quarantine, the woman learned how to play the piano and speak simple Russian.”</p>
<p>The word “quarantine” is often combined with other nouns. In the news and from government announcements you may read about, quarantine guidelines, quarantine authority and quarantine systems.</p>
<p>As a verb, we can say that some young people in the United States are not fully self-quarantining themselves.</p>
<p>So, isolation and quarantine are both ways to help protect the public. They both prevent exposure to people who have or may have a contagious disease.</p>
<hr>
<p>Words in This Story<br>
pandemic – n. medical : an occurrence in which a disease spreads very quickly and affects a large number of people over a wide area or throughout the world</p>
<p>isolate – v. to set apart from others</p>
<p>widow – n. a woman who has lost her spouse or partner by death and usually has not remarried</p>
<p>potential – adj. a chance or possibility that something will happen or exist in the future</p>
<p>authority – n. the power to give orders or make decisions : the power or right to direct or control someone or something</p>
<p>exposure – n. the fact or condition of being affected by something or experiencing something : the condition of being exposed to something</p>
<p>contagious – adj. having a sickness that can be passed to someone else by touching</p>
]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[每天进步一点点-20200428]]></title>
        <id>https://jiangtao639.github.io/jianglab/post/mei-tian-jin-bu-yi-dian-dian-20200428/</id>
        <link href="https://jiangtao639.github.io/jianglab/post/mei-tian-jin-bu-yi-dian-dian-20200428/">
        </link>
        <updated>2020-04-28T02:16:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<figure data-type="image" tabindex="1"><img src="https://jiangtao639.github.io/jianglab//post-images/1588040306827.jpg" alt="" loading="lazy"></figure>
]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<figure data-type="image" tabindex="1"><img src="https://jiangtao639.github.io/jianglab//post-images/1588040306827.jpg" alt="" loading="lazy"></figure>
<!-- more -->
<p>每日一句<br>
Dost thou love life? Then do not squander time, for that's the stuff life is made of.</p>
<!-- more -->
<p>Part1<br>
翻译原文：<br>
-孩子们  这是  张嘴  -不要<br>
在那一刻  勒奈特做了一个决定<br>
想要对付她的孩子们<br>
不能再依靠药物了<br>
当然  随着她的挫败感不断加深<br>
勒奈特认为自我治疗<br>
也无伤大雅<br>
你打算怎么办<br>
永远都不跟我说话了吗<br>
差不多<br>
我想我欠你一个道歉<br>
是么  我可不想让你逼自己<br>
关于你父亲  我不应该说谎<br>
你们不是小孩了  我应该告诉你们真相<br>
对不起<br>
<My Answer><br>
Guys,what's this? open up ur mouth; Nope<br>
Lenate made a decision at that moment<br>
Cannot rely on drugs to deal with her kids<br>
Of course,as her feeling about losing herself and defeated was deepening,<br>
Lenate thought self-treatment was also not a shame<br>
what you intend to do? Never talking with me?<br>
I think you own me an apology to be exact<br>
is it? I don't want you to force yorself<br>
I should't lie ,about your dad<br>
I'd tell you the truth,you are not kid any more<br>
sorry!<br>
<Anwer><br>
Guys, this is a... guys, here... - Nope.<br>
In that moment, Lynette made a decision.<br>
When it came to dealing with her children,<br>
medication was no longer an option.<br>
Of course, given her continuing level of frustration,<br>
Lynette also felt a little<br>
self-medication couldn't hurt.<br>
So what's your strategy?<br>
Are you just never gonna speak to me again?<br>
Something like that.<br>
I suppose I do owe you an apology.<br>
Careful. I wouldn't want you to strain yourself.<br>
I shouldn't have lied to you about your father.<br>
You two are old enough to handle the truth<br>
and I'm sorry.</p>
<!-- more -->
<p>Part2<br>
读完一本书原文：<br>
Mainly to avoid all the staring eyes, Harry looked upward and saw a velvety black ceiling dotted with stars. He heard Hermione whisper, “It’s bewitched to look like the sky outside. I read about it in Hogwarts, A History.”<br>
It was hard to believe there was a ceiling there at all, and that the Great Hall didn’t simply open on to the heavens.<br>
Harry quickly looked down again as Professor McGonagall silently placed a four-legged stool in front of the first years. On top of the stool she put a pointed wizard’s hat. This hat was patched and frayed and extremely dirty. Aunt Petunia wouldn’t have let it in the house.<br>
Maybe they had to try and get a rabbit out of it, Harry thought wildly, that seemed the sort of thing — noticing that everyone in the hall was now staring at the hat, he stared at it, too. For a few seconds, there was complete silence. Then the hat twitched. A rip near the brim opened wide like a mouth — and the hat began to sing:<br>
<My Answer><br>
哈利抬头看去，看见了星星点缀的软绵棉的天花板，主要是为了躲避盯着他的眼睛。他听见赫敏低语道，‘外面的天空使人着迷，我在Hogwarts读过，一段历史’。实在是让人难以相信那里有一块天花板，并且华丽的长廊不仅仅在天空中打开。<br>
当MC教授静静地放了一个四角凳在一年级新生前，哈利迅速的朝下看去。在凳子上他放了一个指向的男巫的帽子。这个帽子是补丁，磨损而且特别脏。P阿姨根本不会让它呆在这个房间的。<br>
或许他们应该试着变一个兔子出来，哈利yy着，似乎就是这类事情。--注意到大厅里的每个人正盯着这个帽子，他也盯着。几秒后陷入了沉寂。然后帽子晃动了，帽子边缘开了一个嘴巴大的裂口--并且帽子开始歌唱<br>
<Anwer><br>
哈利为避开他们的目光，抬头朝上看，只见天鹅绒般漆黑的顶棚上点点星光闪烁。他听见赫敏小声说：“这里施过法术，看起来跟外边的天空一样，我在《霍格沃茨，一段校史》里读到过。”</p>
<p>很难令人相信那上边真有天花板，也很难令人相信餐厅屋顶不是露天的。</p>
<p>麦格教授往一年级新生面前轻轻放了一只四脚凳，哈利连忙收回了目光。麦格教授又往凳子上放了一顶尖顶巫师帽。帽子打着补丁，磨得很旧，而且脏极了。佩妮姨妈决不会让这样的东西进家门。</p>
<p>说不定他们要用这顶帽子变出一只兔子吧，哈利想入非非，大概就是这类事吧—— 他发现餐厅里的人都在盯着这顶帽子，于是他也盯着它。餐厅里鸦雀无声。接着，帽子扭动了。帽边裂开一道宽宽的缝，像一张嘴—— 帽子开始唱起来：<br>
<img src="https://jiangtao639.github.io/jianglab//post-images/1588043380206.jpg" alt="" loading="lazy"></p>
<!-- more -->
<!-- more -->
<!-- more -->
]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA['Breathing Room' Reduces Stress]]></title>
        <id>https://jiangtao639.github.io/jianglab/post/breathing-room-reduces-stress/</id>
        <link href="https://jiangtao639.github.io/jianglab/post/breathing-room-reduces-stress/">
        </link>
        <updated>2020-04-28T02:03:21.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<pre><code>Audio src：https://learningenglish.voanews.com/a/breathing-room-reduces-stress/5367522.html
</code></pre>
<p>If you are feeling nervous or stressed, a simple thing can help. Take a deep breath.</p>
<p>Deep breathing can calm your nerves and lower the chemicals in your body that can lead to stress. If one of your friends is stressed, you can calmly tell them, “Try to take a deep breath.”</p>
<p>We sometimes describe these as deep cleansing breaths. A long, deep breath feels as if it is cleaning out your body.</p>
<p>American English has some expressions that use breath or breathing in them. One expression is breathing room. This may sound like a room used especially for breathing. But it is not.</p>
<p>“Breathing room” gives you time or space to do something, finish something or get relief from something.</p>
<p>It is what the online dictionary Merriam-Webster defines as a “buffer of time, space or money that allows for freedom of movement or relief from a given source of pressure or stress.”</p>
<p>So, time, space and money can all give us breathing room.</p>
<p>Time</p>
<p>First, here is an example related to time.</p>
<p>If you have a big work project or school project that is due in one month, you should start immediately if you can. This will give you some breathing room. If something goes wrong, you will have time to deal with it. Or if something fun comes up, like a party, you will have enough breathing room to be able to enjoy yourself.</p>
<p>If you wait until the very last minute to start your project, you have no breathing room. And that can cause you to feel very stressed.</p>
<p>Money</p>
<p>Now, let’s talk about how money can give you breathing room.</p>
<p>When a country experiences a recession or depression, people who live paycheck-to-paycheck may find themselves in a tough situation. Living paycheck-to-paycheck means you have little money in savings. You need your next paycheck to pay your bills.</p>
<p>However, if you have some money put aside, you might feel less stressed. For example, having enough money in the bank to pay six months of your rent, would give you some breathing room if the economy took a turn for the worse.</p>
<p>Space</p>
<p>Sometimes breathing room refers to actual space around you.</p>
<p>For example, let’s say you witness a car crash. The driver struggles to get out of the car as people gather around to see if he is okay. You step in to make sure there is enough space between the injured driver and the crowd of people. “Step back! Step back! Give him some breathing room!” you shout.</p>
<p>Here is another example. Let’s say you must stay at home because of bad weather, or because of an illness, or because a new virus has turned into a pandemic and is forcing the world inside on a stay-at-home order!</p>
<p>You may find that after a few days -- or even weeks -- you need more breathing room. In other words, you feel like you need more space -- away from those you live with.</p>
<p>So, you can think of it this way: Breathing room reduces stress. It gives you the time, money or space to get something done or to just feel relaxed.</p>
<hr>
<p>Words in This Story<br>
stress – n. a state of mental tension and worry caused by problems in your life, work, etc.</p>
<p>calm – adj. not angry, upset, excited, etc.: calmly – adv.</p>
<p>relief – n. the removal or reducing of something that is painful or unpleasant</p>
<p>buffer – n. something that lessens the harmful effects of (something)</p>
<p>allow – v. to permit (someone) to have or do something</p>
<p>rent – n. money paid for the use of another's property</p>
<p>take a turn for the worse – expression : to become worse</p>
<p>relaxed – adj. set or being at rest or at ease</p>
]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How Fast Is ‘Two Shakes of a Lamb’s Tail’?]]></title>
        <id>https://jiangtao639.github.io/jianglab/post/how-fast-is-two-shakes-of-a-lambs-tail/</id>
        <link href="https://jiangtao639.github.io/jianglab/post/how-fast-is-two-shakes-of-a-lambs-tail/">
        </link>
        <updated>2020-04-27T05:02:21.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>音频链接：https://learningenglish.voanews</p>
<p>原文：<br>
The English language has many expressions that describe a fast-moving event. Some expressions relate to body movements. We say something happens in the blink of an eye or in a heartbeat. Other expressions are related to the world of nature.</p>
<p>Today we will talk about a speed-related expression involving an animal. Now, because we are talking about speed and animals, you might think it is a big cat, such as a lion or cheetah -- or maybe even a small, but speedy animal such as a hare.</p>
<p>But it is none of them.</p>
<p>You guessed it!</p>
<p>The expression today involves sheep – baby lambs to be exact!</p>
<p>But why? Lambs are cute. But they are not really known for their lightning speed. Well, our expression is about a specific part of the animal – its tail.</p>
<p>I suspect lambs can shake their tails very fast. Because when something happens quickly, we say it happens in “two shakes of a lamb’s tail.” Here is an example:</p>
<p>“I’m going to the store. I’ll be back in two shakes of a lamb’s tail!”</p>
<p>This expression is a cuter and more descriptive way of saying “quickly.” Maybe instead of sending a text message with the letters BRB (be right back), we could use the image of a lamb shaking its tail. That would fun!</p>
<p>Being cute like a lamb may be fun. But it has its drawbacks. Cute things are often not taken seriously. And this cute factor is the main reason Americans rarely use “two shakes of a lamb’s tail” in a serious situation.</p>
<p>For example, if I see a person get hit by a car, I would not say, “Hold on! Help will be here in two shakes of a lamb’s tail!”</p>
<p>That would not make the injured person lying in the middle of the street feel reassured. In an emergency like that, I would say something like, “Help is on the way!”</p>
<p>Generally speaking, an emergency is not a good time to use cute animal expressions.</p>
<p>Some language experts say “two shakes of a lamb’s tail” was first used in written English in the 1800s. They think that it was used in spoken English much earlier than that.</p>
<p>You should know that we often shorten this expression to simply “two shakes” – as in, “I’ll be there in two shakes!”</p>
<p>You should not use that one for emergencies either.</p>
<p>And that is Words and Their Stories for this week. But we will be back in two shakes of a lamb’s tail. Well, actually…we’ll be back next week!</p>
<!--Vocabulary -->
<pre><code>________________________________________________________________
</code></pre>
<p>cute – adj. attractive in looks or actions</p>
<p>tail – n. the rear part of an animal or a usually slender flexible growth that extends from this part</p>
<p>drawback – n. something that causes problems​</p>
<p>factor – n. something that helps produce or influence a result : one of the things that cause something to happen</p>
<p>reassured – v. to make (someone) feel less afraid, upset, or doubtful</p>
]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[每天进步一点点]]></title>
        <id>https://jiangtao639.github.io/jianglab/post/mei-tian-jin-bu-yi-dian-dian/</id>
        <link href="https://jiangtao639.github.io/jianglab/post/mei-tian-jin-bu-yi-dian-dian/">
        </link>
        <updated>2020-04-27T04:10:58.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>每日一句<br>
Everyone is born with genius, but most people only keep it a few minutes.</p>
<p>IT翻译原文：<br>
OS microkernel<br>
Extensibility is enhanced because many components previously considered to be parts of the OS kernel, e.g. process scheduling, now reside outside it in the OS. These components can be replaced at will to modify or extend the OS behaviour. It is thus possible to use the same microkernel to implement time sharing or dedicated real time systems. This simplifies the development of an OS for a new application domain.</p>
<p>&lt;我的翻译&gt;<br>
Operating System 微内核<br>
因为许多成分先前被认为是微内核的组分，例如进程计划，现在已被排除在操作系统外，所以可延伸性是提升了。这些组分可以根据意愿被替换来修改或者延申OS的功能。因此使用相同的为微内核系统来完成时间共享或专门实时系统是可能的。这简化了OS在新应用领域的发展。</p>
<p>&lt;答案&gt;<br>
由于以前被认为是内核一部分的组件(如进程调度)现在被放在内核之外，因此可扩充性也增强了。如果想修改或扩展系统性能，可以通过替换这些组件实现，可以使用同一个微内核来实现分时或实时系统，这简化了在新的应用域中对操作系统的开发。</p>
<p>读完一本书翻译原文：<br>
Now when Squealer described the scene so graphically, it seemed to the animals that they did remember it. At any rate, they remembered that at the critical moment of the battle Snowball had turned to flee. But Boxer was still a little uneasy.<br>
‘I do not believe that Snowball was a traitor at the beginning,’ he said finally. ‘What he has done since is different. But I believe that at the Battle of the Cowshed he was a good comrade.’<br>
‘Our Leader, Comrade Napoleon,’ announced Squealer, speaking very slowly and firmly, ‘has stated categorically — categorically, comrade — that Snowball was Jones’s agent from the very beginning — yes, and from long before the Rebellion was ever thought of.’<br>
‘Ah, that is different!’ said Boxer. ‘If Comrade Napoleon says it, it must be<br>
right.’<br>
‘That is the true spirit, comrade!’ cried Squealer, but it was noticed he cast a very ugly look at Boxer with his little twinkling eyes. He turned to go, then paused and added impressively: ‘I warn every animal on this farm to keep his eyes very wide open. For we have reason to think that some of Snowball’s secret agents are lurking among us at this moment! ’</p>
<p>&lt;我的翻译&gt;<br>
现在当S图像化的描绘情景时，动物们好像确实记得这件事。至少，他们记得在战斗的关键时刻雪球已经转为逃避。但是拳击手仍有点不适。<br>
我不相信雪球一开始就是个叛徒，他最终说到，<br>
翻译不下去了，什么脑残情节！罢工ps这本书是《动物世界》</p>
<!-- Answer -->
<p>既然斯奎拉把那一场景描述得如此形象生动，动物们便似乎觉得，他们果真记得有这么回事。不管怎么说，他们记得在激战的关键时刻，斯诺鲍曾经掉头逃过。但是鲍克瑟还有一些感到不自在。</p>
<p>他终于说道：“我不相信斯诺鲍一开始就是一个叛徒。他后来的所作所为是另一回事，但我认为在牛棚大战中，他是一个好同志。”</p>
<p>“我们的领袖，拿破仑同志，”斯奎拉以缓慢而坚定的语气宣告，“已经明确地——明确了，同志们——声明斯诺鲍一开始就是琼斯的奸细，是的，远在想着起义前就是的。”</p>
<p>“噢，这就不一样了！如果这是拿破仑同志说的，那就肯定不会错。”鲍克瑟说。</p>
<p>“这是事实的真相，同志们！”斯奎拉大叫着。但动物们注意到他那闪亮的小眼睛向鲍克瑟怪模怪样地瞥了一眼。在他转身要走时，停下来又强调了一句：“我提醒庄园的每个动物要睁大眼睛。我们有理由相信，眼下，斯诺鲍的密探正在我们中间潜伏着！</p>
]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[第一次建站，冲冲冲！]]></title>
        <id>https://jiangtao639.github.io/jianglab/post/di-yi-ci-jian-zhan-chong-chong-chong/</id>
        <link href="https://jiangtao639.github.io/jianglab/post/di-yi-ci-jian-zhan-chong-chong-chong/">
        </link>
        <updated>2020-04-26T15:17:00.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>分享一段代码吧<br>
from turtle  import *</p>
<p>color('black','red')<br>
begin_fill()</p>
<p>penup()<br>
goto (50,50)<br>
pendown()</p>
<p>right(45)<br>
goto(100,0)<br>
left(90)<br>
fd(120)<br>
circle(50,225)</p>
<p>penup()<br>
goto(0,0)<br>
pendown()</p>
<p>left(135)<br>
fd(120)<br>
circle(50,225)<br>
seth(90)<br>
circle(50,225)</p>
<p>fd(121)<br>
end_fill()<br>
left(56)</p>
<p>penup()<br>
goto(-210,40)<br>
pendown()<br>
goto(0,80)<br>
penup()<br>
goto(160,110)<br>
pendown()<br>
goto(320,140)</p>
<p>done()</p>
]]></content>
    </entry>
</feed>